<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Choria AAA Service</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/index.html</link><description>Recent content on Choria AAA Service</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/installtion/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/installtion/index.html</guid><description>We distribute an RPM or Docker container for the AAA Service package. Debian is not supported at present.
YUM Repository For RPMs we publish releases but also nightly builds to our repositories.
Users of our Puppet modules will already have these repositories available.
Release [choria_release] name=Choria Orchestrator Releases mirrorlist=http://mirrorlists.choria.io/yum/release/el/$releasever/$basearch.txt enabled=True gpgcheck=True repo_gpgcheck=True gpgkey=https://choria.io/RELEASE-GPG-KEY metadata_expire=300 sslcacert=/etc/pki/tls/certs/ca-bundle.crt sslverify=True Nightly Nightly releases are named and versioned aaasvc-0.99.0.20221109-1.el7.x86_64.rpm where the last part of the version is the date.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/configuration/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/configuration/index.html</guid><description>Configuring the AAA Service requires exact knowledge of your deployment scenarios, we support 2 major approaches:
Deployment for users with Certificate Authorities and puppet, file, certmanager or pkcs11 Choria Security System (the default) Deployment for users with ED25519 based Organization Issuers and the choria Choria Security System Most users, today, will fall in the first category.
General Requirements Authenticator You have to decide on an Authentication system to use.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring</title><link>https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/monitoring/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://choria-io.github.io/aaasvc/monitoring/index.html</guid><description>The AAA Service keep statistics in the Prometheus format, using this you can see graphs of allow/denies but also get granular statistics for every Agent and Action.
All the statics have a site label allowing you to easily aggregate a global cluster of AAA Services.
Statistic Description choria_aaa_auditor_errors Total number of audit requests that failed choria_aaa_authenticator_errors Total number of authentication requests that failed choria_aaa_authenticator_time Time taken to handle logins choria_aaa_authorizer_allowed Total number of requests that were allowed choria_aaa_authorizer_denied Total number of requests that were denied choria_aaa_authorizer_errors Total number of requests could not be authorized choria_aaa_signer_errors Total number of requests that could not be signed choria_aaa_signer_allowed Total number of requests that were allowed by the authorizer choria_aaa_signer_denied Total number of requests that were denied by the authorizer choria_aaa_signer_invalid_token Total number of requests that contained invalid tokens choria_aaa_build_info Build information about the running instance We have a published Grafana Dashboard for this statistics.</description></item></channel></rss>